(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T05:18:32.942303",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
空にある何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
you told me they were stars.
まるでそれは僕らみたいに寄り添ってる
Just like us, they nestle close together.
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Through tears, smiles, and bonds we share.
何十回何百回ぶつかり合って
We clash tens, hundreds of times,
何十年何百年 昔の光が
and light from tens, hundreds of years ago
星自身も忘れたころに 僕らに届いてる
reaches us long after the stars forgot it.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って 同じ空
We found and pulled toward each other under the same sky,
輝くんだって 二人だって 約束した
promising that the two of us would shine together.
遥か遠く 終わらないペテルギウス 誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Far away, an endless Betelgeuse, magic connecting us all.
僕ら肩並べ 手を取り合って 進んでいく
Standing shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand as we move forward.
辛い時だって 泣かないって 誓っただろう
Vowing not to cry even in times of pain.
遥か遠く 終わらないペテルギウス 君にも見えるだろう 祈りが
Far away, an endless Betelgeuse, can you see this prayer too?
君がいつだってそこにいてくれること
Knowing you're always there for me
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
is just like the starlight shining down.
今日も泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Today too, we laugh, cry, and connect.
空にあった何かを見つめていたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
you told me they were stars.
まるでそれは僕らみたいに寄り添ってる
Just like us, they nestle close,
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
at times crying, laughing, and connecting.
記憶を辿って蘇るよ
Tracing memories, it revives,
君がいつでもそこに居てくれること
the fact that you're always there.
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
Just like the light of the stars,
今日にも泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
today too, crying, laughing, and connecting.
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Clashing tens and hundreds of times,
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
a light from tens and hundreds of years ago
星自身も忘れたころに僕らに届いている
reaches us by the time the stars forgot.
僕ら見つけ合って手繰り合って同じ空
We found each other, under the same sky
輝くのだって二人だって約束した
promoted to shine together, we promised.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス 誰かに繋ぐ魔法
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse, magic connecting us.
僕ら 肩並べ 手を取り合って 進んでく
We stand shoulder to shoulder, hand in hand, moving forward.
辛い時だって 泣かないって 誓ったんだろう
Vowing never to cry even in times of pain.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, a never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう 祈りが
you can see the prayer too, don't you?
記憶を辿って蘇るよ
Tracing memories, it revives,
君がいつでもそこに居てくれること
the fact that you're always there.
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
Just like the light of the stars,
今日にも泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
today too, crying, laughing, and connecting.
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Clashing tens and hundreds of times,
何十年 何百年 昔の光が 僕らを照らしている
a light from long ago shines upon us.
僕ら見つけ合って手繰り合って同じ空 輝くのだって二人だって約束した
We found each other under the same sky, promising to shine together.
はーい！ハローロボコ！
Hii! Hello Roboco!
はーい、今日は何の日かっていうと、そう！僕の7歳の誕生日！
Hii, what day is it today, you ask? That's right! It's my 7th birthday!
いやー、僕ももう7歳になっちゃいましたよ！というわけで
Man, I've already turned 7 years old! And so,
ホロライブ0期生 バーチャルロボットのロボ子だよー！
I'm Roboco, Hololive 0th Gen virtual robot!
みんな気づいた？そうなんだよ。
Did everyone notice? That's right.
実は、実は！ほら見て！なんと！今回から肌が出せるように進化しましたー！どうこれ！？
Actually, actually! Look! Guess what! Starting this time, I've evolved so my skin shows! How's this?!
すごい新鮮じゃないですか？
Isn't it super refreshing?
はーい、というわけで、今回はですね #ロボ子爆誕2023 もちろんあります！
Hii, so for this time, of course #RobocoBirth2023 is here!
えー、こちらのほうに書いてある…あ、こっちだって！
Um, written over here... Ah, I mean over here!
はい、ということでこっちに書いてある、えー、#ロボ子爆誕2023 が今回の配信のハッシュタグなので、みんなぜひつぶやいてトレンド入り目指してください！
Yes, so written right here, um, #RobocoBirth2023 is the hashtag for this stream, so everyone please tweet it and aim for the trending list!
誕生日トレンド入りしたいです！お願いします！
I want to trend on my birthday! Please!
というわけで、そうなんですよ。ロボ子なんと7歳になっちゃいましたもう7歳だって！やったー！ラッキーセブンじゃないですか！今年はいいことありそうだな！
So yeah, that's right. Roboco has turned 7 years old already, 7 years old! Yay! Isn't that a lucky seven? Looks like good things are coming this year!
高性能が止まらない歳になりそうだな！あ！なんか聞こえましたよ。
Looks like an unstoppable year of high performance! Ah! I heard something.
そう、実はステージが今回、どどーん！かっこいいでしょ！
That's right, actually, the stage this time is... ta-da! Isn't it cool?!
今回おしゃれなステージを用意させていただきました！え、めちゃめちゃかっこよくない！？ロボ子すごくない！？これ！
We had such a stylish stage prepared for us this time! Eh, isn't it super cool?! Isn't Roboco amazing?! Look at this!
というわけで今日はこのステージでたくさんたくさん歌って踊っていきたいと思うので、
So today, I want to sing and dance a whole lot on this stage,
みなさんまだまだ楽しみにして、ぜひ楽しんでいってください！
so everyone, look forward to it and please enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
ふふふ、今日はなんとまだお披露目してないあの衣装の全身が、あったりしなかったり！？えー！？
Fufufu, today, could it be that the full body of that outfit we haven't revealed yet is... or isn't there?! Eh?!
最後までたくさん楽しみに待っててくださいねー！それでは次の曲に行ってみたいたいと思います！どうぞ！
Please wait forward to it with lots of excitement until the very end! Now then, I'd like to try moving on to the next song! Here we go!
ひらりふらりさ迷ってく
Wandering aimlessly,
白い夢はもうやめた
I've given up on white dreams.
私ずっとしてたのに匂いに誘われて
Lured by the scent I'd always known,
落ちてく
I fall and fall away.
与えられた運命を訪ねることが怖くて
Frightened to uncover my true fate,
流れる日々の答えに濁したのは心だけ
Blurring the answers found in flowing days—
心だけ
That was all it was.
さだめられた箱の中あじけないなさびしさが
Lacking any courage, locked within the box,
少し会うしうしてたの片思いも知らぬまま
I wandered, barely missing you all along.
しまい込んだはずだったただのざれ言も
Keeping my secrets hidden away,
わかってる奥に潜むその目で見た紛れもない鼓動を
Even if I tell a lie with the eyes hidden deep inside...
ひらりゆらり飛んでゆける
Flitting, fluttering, I fly away.
迷い迷い閉じ込めた
Lost and drifting, I sink in deep.
あなたもう話さないで
You won't even speak to me,
やがて嘘をついても
Even if you tell a lie.
ひらりふらりさ迷ってく
Flitting, fluttering, wandering aimlessly,
白い夢はもうやめた
I've given up on white dreams.
私ずっとしてたのに匂いに誘われて
Lured by the scent I'd always known,
落ちてく
I fall and fall away.
まとわりつく言葉だけ何のいみもないくせに
Spinning words that mean nothing at all,
背負されてる重さに潰れそうでもがい てた
I felt crushed under the heavy burden.
傷がないふりしていたもこうわさすべてを囁いた
Whispering every broken truth,
わざに染まる覚悟とかあもさの大丈夫それだけ
I'll accept the darkness.
ひらりゆらり舞い降りてく
Flitting, fluttering, I lose my way,
迷い迷い閉じ込めた
Lost and drifting, I sink in deep.
あなたもう話さないで
You won't even speak to me,
やがて嘘をついても
Even if you tell a lie.
ひらりふらり落とされてく
Flitting, fluttering, as I fall down,
白い夢はもうやめた私きっと戻らぬいに誘われて
I'm sure white dreams will never return.
落ちてく
I fall and fall away.
ひらりゆらり飛んでゆける
Flitting, fluttering, I fly away.
迷い迷い閉じ込めた
Lost and drifting, I sink in deep.
あなたもう話さないで
You won't even speak to me,
やがて嘘をついても
Even if you tell a lie.
ひらりふらりさ迷ってく
Flitting, fluttering, wandering aimlessly,
白い夢はもうやめた
I've given up on white dreams.
私ずっとしてたのに匂いに誘われて
Lured by the scent I'd always known,
落ちてく
I fall and fall away.
ちゅ、多様性。
Chu, diversity.
我愛你 酔いが覚めない
Wo-ai-ni, I still can't shake off the hangover,
oh, i need you 恋が覚めない
Oh, I need you, I'm still hopelessly in love.
お生憎様の慣れ果て察して
Surrendering to the usual routine...
無問題 破滅してみて
No problem, go ahead and ruin it all.
hold me tight トラウマの味
Hold me tight, the taste of trauma.
猛反対 お手合わせでお手 ハイ♡報酬
Total opposition, polite as can be—high! Reward.
喉の奥がチクンチ クン
A tingling deep in my throat,
僕はドクン ドクン
My heart goes dokun-dokun.
鼓動で孤独消してみてよ
Try using your heartbeat to wash away the loneliness.
愛 も 恋 も 独占 し て
Keep love, romance, and obsession all to yourself,
我愛你 酔いが覚めない
Wo ai ni, I can't sober up
oh, i need you 恋が冷めない
oh, i need you, the love won't fade
お生憎様の慣れ果て察して
Guess the miserable fate of your misfortune
無問題 破滅してみて
No problem, try destroying yourself
hold me tight トラウマの味
Hold me tight, the taste of trauma
猛反対 お手 お座りで はい 報酬
Total opposition, sit down, here's your reward
get get get on ! get get get on !
Get get get on! Get get get on!
get on chu !
Get on chu!
get get get on ! get get get get on chu !
Get get get on! Get get get get on chu!
熱くトロけるくらいに溢れた気持ちがたまらないでしょ
Your overflowing feelings are too much to handle
たまらないでしょ
I can't take it anymore!
get get get on ! get get get on !
Get get get on! Get get get on!
get on chu !
Get on chu!
get get get on ! get get get get on chu !
Get get get on! Get get get get on chu!
get on ! get on !
Get on! Get on!
我愛你 もうまんたい
Wo ai ni, moumantai
get get get on chu !
Get get get on chu!
ポン・チー・カン 勝負はいつも頓珍漢
Pon chii kan, games are always nonsensical
僕に言わせりゃちんぷんかんぷんだ最後はロンでしょ？
If you ask me, it's total gibberish, ending with ron?
もう何回？ 殺されればいい
How many times? Just kill me already
oh, one night 忘れられない終わんないで
Oh, one night, unforgettable, don't end yet
トキメキ偏愛♡予習
Heart-pounding obsessive love rehearsal
喉の奥がチクンチクン
The back of my throat tingles and aches
僕はドクンドクン
My heart beats wildly
心臓ごと引きずり出してみてよ
Show me, pulling it out with my very heartbeat
気持ちいいね 面倒くさいけど
It feels good, though it's a hassle
やっぱ照れくさいけど
Still, it's kind of embarrassing, but
死ぬまで忘れられないチュウしよ
Let's kiss until we die, never forgetting it
いかれた街はゾンビで溢れる
The crazy town is overflowing with zombies
君は僕に恋してる
You are in love with me
ときめく胸に繋がるロープを引なよ
Pull on the rope connected to my thumping chest
いくよ
Here we go!
bet bet bet on ! bet bet bet on ! bet on chu !
Bet bet bet on! Bet bet bet on! Bet on chu!
bet bet bet on ! bet bet bet bet on chu !
Bet bet bet on! Bet bet bet bet on chu!
マジで狂えるくらいの鬱鬱しさ/鬱鬱しさが美しいでしょ
The madness of being truly crazy is beautiful, right?
...
Pulling strings...
get get get on ! get get get on ! get on chu !
Get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
get get get on ! get get get get on chu !
Get get get on! Get get get get on chu!
せーの
Ready, set!
ポン・チー・カン
Pon chii kan!
終わんない
Never ending...
get get get on chu !
Get get get on chu!
ほらね
See?
我愛你 もうまんたい
Wo ai ni, moumantai
get get get on chu !
Get get get on chu!
ロボ子さんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday to Robocosan!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
呼んでもらってめちゃめちゃ嬉しいんですけど
I'm so happy you called me, I'm super duper happy!
かなたのこの衣装が出たときから一緒に歌いたくてうずうずしてた
Ever since this outfit was revealed, I've been dying to sing this together!
もう本当に嬉しくてもう即このオファーが来たときに「もう絶対やります！」って言ったんですけど
I was so happy, I said "I'm totally doing this" right away!
ちょっと今回二人並んでみて
But this time, standing side by side...
本当にシナジーありますよねこのルックス
We really do have great synergy, right?
そうだよ！みんな見て見てこれ！
Look, everyone, look!
赤と青でこれどう？二人組みたいじゃね？
Red and blue, how is this?
そうだよね！
Right?
全部もうすごくない？可愛すぎる！
Everything is just amazing and super cute!
一部は真反対なんだけどさ
Part of it is completely opposite though...
そうそうそうそう！
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
一部はどことは言わないけど、え、お、お、え、う、うん、え？
Part of it—well, I won't say which part—is like...
え、色の話かと思った、そうそうそうえ？
Wait, I thought we were talking about colors!
何の話してるのってロボ子先輩！
What are you talking about, Robocosan?!
そこは反対じゃないでしょ全然！そこは大丈夫でしょうよ！
That's not opposite at all! You're fine, don't worry!
びっくりした、あ、これいい衣装か！
Wait, this is a great outfit!
いやいや一緒ですよ！もう急に、嫌だなぁ、全然それだと思わなくて、はいはいはい
Yeah, yeah, it's together! Suddenly I was like, wait, no way!
あ、これ揃ったなと思ったんだよ、カメラをもっと見とけばさ、ね、これね
I thought "Oh, we're matched," and I was looking at the camera like...
違うわ！びっくり！
Different! Completely different!
もう気付くわさすがに最終的に！
You only realize that at the very end!
いやね、でも、今回この楽曲も僕実はずつと気になってたんで
Yeah, well, this song, I've actually been wondering about it for a while.
そうやっぱさ、そう、この衣装に何が合うのかなって思ったら、最近やっぱちゅ、多様性。
Right, I thought, "What matches this outfit?" And recently, "Chu, Tayousei."
来てて僕の中で！
...had been on my mind!
やばかりますよ！似合うんじゃないの？可愛いんじゃないの？って思って誘っちゃったよね！
I knew it! Doesn't it suit us? Isn't it cute?
いやもうめちゃめちゃ嬉しいし、やっぱりこの曲って流れたときにロボ子先輩にぴったりだなあって思いましたよね！
I'm so happy, and whenever this song plays, I think it fits Robocosan perfectly!
いや僕もかなたに似合うなって思ったよ！え、そうそう？合ってくるとこれ！
And I thought it really suited you too!
いやいや、そう合いすぎる！やばい！ありがとー！ずむずむ！
It fits so well! Oh, scary! Thank you so much!
いや、じゃあこれ次もですね、なんかあのゲストがいるのかな？
So, next, um... is there a guest?
なんかあのすごい清楚な香りが...
There's this pure scent...
あ、してる、ふふ、後ろから清楚を感じる、ふふ、ふふ
I can smell it from behind!
私は次のゲストと交代してまいります！ロボ子先輩ありがとー！ありがとー！またねー！バイバーイ！
I will hand over to the next guest! Robocosan, thank you!
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let's laugh away our sadness,
生きるってマリオネット
Living like a marionette.
心臓がスイングしたら
If your heart starts to swing,
琴琴はいかが？
How about a harp?
1・2・2・1・2・2
1, 2, 2, 1, 2, 2,
1・2・2・3
1, 2, 2, 3.
私上手く踊れないわ
I can't dance very well.
痛みも 恨みも 悲しみも
All the pain, resentment, and sorrow,
混ぜて 混ぜて こねて こねて
Mix them, mix them, knead them, knead them,
おやすみのキス
And say goodnight with a kiss.
shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance away,
絶望 欲求 this is the life!
Despair and desire, this is the life!
shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで ひとつになりましょう
Don't think about unnecessary things, let's become one.
いいな いいな いいな いいな 人間って
How nice, how nice, how nice, how nice to be human!
泣きたいのに笑えちゃう
Even though I want to cry, I find myself laughing.
人生ってピエロ
Life is like a clown.
本当の心隠して
Hiding my true heart,
笑うフリをするの
I put on a smiling face.
1・2・2・1・2・2
1, 2, 2, 1, 2, 2,
1・2・2・3
1, 2, 2, 3.
私上手く生きれないわ
I can't live my life properly.
本音も ウソも 不安も
Truth, lies, and anxiety alike,
溶かして 溶かして 蓋して 蓋して
Melt them, melt them, cover them, cover them,
おやすみなさい
Good night.
shall we dream? 夢見ましょう
Shall we dream? Let's dream away,
眠ても 覚めても this is the life!
Sleeping or waking, this is the life!
shadow life!
目を閉じて いないこと 全部 全部 忘れましょう
Close your eyes and forget everything bad.
shall we dance? 不器用でも
Shall we dance? Clumsy though we are,
あがいて もがいて this is the life!
Struggling and writhing, this is the life!
shadow step?
余計なこと考えないで ステップを踏み鳴らせ！
Don't think about unnecessary things, stomp out the beat!
shall we smile? 今 だけ は 一緒に 笑ってみませんか
Shall we smile? Just for now, won't you smile with me?
shadow dance!
今 だけ はぜんぶ 忘れて
For now, let's forget it all,
一緒に飛びましょう
And fly away together.
(show!)
悲しみは笑いましょう
Let's laugh away our sadness,
生きるってマリオネット
Living like a marionette.
心臓がスイングしたら
If your heart starts to swing,
琴琴はいかが？
How about a harp?
1・2・2・1・2・2
1, 2, 2, 1, 2, 2,
1・2・2・3
1, 2, 2, 3.
私上手く踊れないわ
I can't dance very well.
痛みも 恨みも 悲しみも
All the pain, resentment, and sorrow,
混ぜて 混ぜて こねて こねて
Mix them, mix them, knead them, knead them,
おやすみのキス
And say goodnight with a kiss.
shall we smile? 今 だけ は
Shall we smile? Just for now,
一緒に笑ってみませんか
Won't you smile with me?
shadow dance!
今 だけ は ぜんぶ 忘れて
For now, let's forget it all,
一緒に飛びましょう
And fly away together.
(show!)
shall we dance? 踊りましょう
Shall we dance? Let's dance away,
絶望 欲求 this is the life!
Despair and desire, this is the life!
shadow life!
余計なこと考えないで ひとつになりましょう
Don't think about unnecessary things, let's become one.
いいな いいな いいな いいな 人間って
How nice, how nice, how nice, how nice to be human!
人間って
Being human!
いいな いいな いいな いいな 人間って
How nice, how nice, how nice, how nice to be human!
人間って
Being human!
いいな
So nice!
ロボ子さーん！ おめでとー！
Roboco-san! Happy birthday!
お誕生日おめでとーー！ ありがとうーー！
Happy birthday! Thank you so much!
いや、なんかさっきあずきの話してました？
Hey, were you guys talking about Azuki just now?
なんか、香ってた？
Did you smell something?
いやなんかちょっと、かなたの後ろから視線とちょっと匂いが…
Well, I felt a gaze and kind of a smell coming from behind Kanata...
匂いは届いてた？
Did the smell reach you?
清爽の香りがしたなって思って
I thought, "Ah, that refreshing fragrance is here."
本当？本当？
Really? Really?
ということなので皆さん、あずきでーす！
So everyone, it's Azuki!
あずきちゃんでーす！
It's Azuki-chan!
やっと…えっ、本当？
Finally... Wait, really?
ほんとに久しぶり！
It's been so long!
ねー
Right!
やっと歌えたよ、二人で
We finally got to sing together, the two of us!
そう、一緒に！
Yeah, together!
なんと今回ロボ子さんがシャルイダンスを選曲してくれたんですけど
And amazingly, Roboco-san selected "Sharu-I Dance" for us this time,
ロボ子さん選曲理由はどんなところに?
Roboco-san, what was your reason for choosing it?
えー、もうだってさ、会うたびにさ
Well, because every time we meet,
うん、もう「ぼくたちはやっぱりビスパ曲一緒に歌いたいよね」って
yeah, we'd say, "We definitely want to sing Bispa songs together!"
いやそう、そう、もうロボ子さんとビスパーね、この感じで歌いたいと思ってて
Exactly, yeah! We wanted to sing in this vibe with Roboco and Bispa,
そうそうそう。だからこのシャルイダンスを一緒に歌えてめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです、あずきは。
That's right! So AZKi is super happy to sing 'Sharu-I Dance' together.
マジで似合ってた！あのなんか
It really suited you! Like,
僕たち二人しかいないのになんか多いね
even though there's only two of us, there seem to be a lot?
おいおいね、あ、ほんとだ、おいね
Hey, hey, oh right, hey!
あ、みんな気づいてると思うけど
I think everyone's noticed, but
今日なんかね、影がついてるんだよね
today, you know, we have shadows?
なんと、黒子さんですか?
What, are they Kuroko?
黒子さんがいますね
There are Kuroko here.
あれ、同じ動きがしちゃう？しちゃう？しちゃうんですね
Wait, are our movements matching? Matching? They match!
増えたってこと？
Does that mean we increased?
増えたってこと、ロボ子さんは増えたのか、1人ずつ
Does it mean Roboco-san increased one by one?
分身できてしかも衣装が違うと
We can make clones and even have different outfits!
え、高性能ってこと？
Eh, high performance?
高性能なんだな
High performance!
1回の踊りで2つの衣装が見れるなんてなかなかないからね
It's rare to see two outfits in one dance performance.
ねえ、なかなかない
Yeah, super rare.
ということであずきはこのクロコと一緒に帰ろうと思います
So AZKi is going to go home with this Kuroko.
1匹もらおうと思ってたのに
Even though I thought I'd get one!
もらっていきます、仲良く
We'll take them, get along well!
はい、この後も頑張ってください！
Yes, please do your best after this too!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうね！またね！またねー！
Thank you! See you later! Bye-bye!
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice,
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
If you pierce through, you approach being a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
Close those eyes and if you touch,
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
A demon with the same shape and body temperature.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Is it bad for me, but fine for him?
そこに壁があっただけなのに
Even though there was just a wall there,
生まれきてしまった 運命嘆くな
Don't lament the fate you were born with.
僕らはみんな 自由なんだから
Because we are all free.
鳥のように 羽根があれば
If we had wings like birds,
どこへだって行けるけれど
We could go anywhere,
帰る場所が なければ
But if there's no place to return to,
きっとどこへも行けない
Surely we can't go anywhere.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I don't just want to live.
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛すよ
The world is cruel, but I still love you.
なにを犠牲にしても それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you.
間違いだとしても 疑ったりしない
Even if it's a mistake, I won't doubt it.
正しさとは 自分のこと 強く信じることだ
Righteousness is strongly believing in yourself.
鉄の雨が 降り散る情景
The scene of iron rain falling,
テレビの中 映画に見えたんだ
It looked like a movie on TV.
戦争なんて 愚かな兇暴
War is such foolish brutality,
関係ない 知らない国の話
A story of an unknown country that doesn't concern me.
それならなんで あいつ憎んで
If that's the case, why do I hate him,
黒い気持ち 隠しきれないわけ説明だって
And why can't I hide my dark feelings?
できないんだ / 僕らはなんて 矛盾ばかりなんだ
I can't even explain it. / We are such contradictions.
この言葉も 訳されれば
Even if these words are translated,
本当の意味は 伝わらない
The true meaning won't be conveyed.
信じるのは その目を開いて 触れた世界だけ
What to believe is, opening your eyes, only the world you touched.
怯えるのは その目を開いて 触れた世界だけ
Being frightened, opening your eyes, only the world you touched.
ただただ生きるのは嫌だ
I don't just want to live.
世界は残酷だ それでも君を愛すよ
The world is cruel, but I still love you.
なにを犠牲にしても それでも君を守るよ
No matter what I sacrifice, I will still protect you.
それでも君を守るよ
I will still protect you.
鉄の弾が 正義の証明
An iron bullet is proof of justice.
貫けば 英雄に近づいた
Piercing through, I grew close to a hero.
その目を閉じて 触れてみれば
If you close those eyes and touch it,
同じ形 同じ体温の悪魔
a devil with the same form and warmth.
僕はダメで あいつはいいの?
Why am I bad while he is fine?
繁華街 地下 場末のバーは
In a downtown underground back-alley bar,
ボンクラ酔いどれ自称非凡人
drunken fools, self-proclaimed extraordinary people,
使い捨てしたいクソと されたいヤカラに似て大繁盛
thriving with trash wanting to be used and punks wanting to be used.
混ぜ物多めの安価なバーボン 半端なアンタが良く似合う
Cheap bourbon with lots of mixers suits a half-assed punk like you.
酔っぱらおう同じ事 なんてのがお決まりなんだけど
Getting drunk and doing the same old thing is the rule, but...
人は孤独を殺すため 虚しいを戻すため酒を飲むんだ
People drink alcohol to kill their loneliness and wash away emptiness.
金も時間も肝臓も なあ何でもやるからさ
Money, time, liver... hey, I'll do anything for you, so
二人でいい? 良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に
can we be together? Even before talking about good or bad,
俺には一切記憶がねえんだよ
I have absolutely no memory left at all!
明日もまた猛弁解 飲んだら明日に響くと言うけれど
Making fierce excuses again tomorrow—they say drinking affects tomorrow,
飲まなきゃその明日すらねえんだよ
but if I don't drink, there won't even be a tomorrow!
嫌になるぜもう一杯 don't stop 構わずもう一杯
It makes me sick, give me another drink. Don't stop, pour another without caring.
明日の行方も今夜の便も 全部無くして尚大繁盛
Losing tomorrow's whereabouts and tonight's flight, it's still thriving more than ever!
プライドと理性捨てりゃ 愛を偽るのは簡単だ
If you throw away pride and reason, faking love is easy.
「しー」人差し指で黙らせて 以下略 午前2時
"Shh," silencing with an index finger, et cetera, 2 AM.
結局いつもの事と言うやおまおしまいなんだけど
In the end, it's the usual story and ends at that, but...
人は誰しも偽善者さ 優しい嘘を餌に狩りをするんだ
Everyone is a hypocrite, hunting using gentle lies as bait.
血酒火の酒苦しい酒 ねえ優しくするからさ
Blood wine, fire wine, bitter wine... hey, I'll be gentle, so
一人は嫌だ 愛だの恋だのやんややと騒ぐが
I hate being alone. People make a fuss about love and romance,
酔ったら結局誰でもいいんだよ 荒ぶれて暴言タイム
but once drunk, anyone is fine in the end—it's wild profanity time.
その「誰でも」すら俺は選ばれず 泣くのもダメさ酒を浴びたよ
Even for that "anyone," I'm not chosen. Can't even cry, so I drenched myself in alcohol.
嫌になるぜもう一杯 can't stop 意味もなくもう一杯
It makes me sick, another cup! Can't stop, another cup for no reason!
馬鹿と煙が梯子酒 登る様はさながら蜘蛛の糸
Fools and smoke love crawl-drinking; climbing like a spider's thread.
何処もかしこもクソだらけってオイ一番クソなのはオマエだ馬鹿
Everywhere is full of crap—hey, the biggest piece of crap is you, idiot!
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に 俺には一切記憶がねえんだよ
Even before talking about good or bad, I have absolutely no memory left!
嫌になるぜもう限界 飲んでもいないのに難なく生きてる
I'm sick of it, I've reached my limit. Living so effortlessly without even drinking—
アンタの方こそ飲まれてるんだよ 嫌になるぜもう一杯
you're the one who's being consumed by it! It makes me sick, give me another drink.
won't stop 死ぬ前にもう一杯
Won't stop, one more cup before I die!
爆と煙が梯子酒 登る様はさながら蜘蛛の糸
Roaring sound and smoke, bar-hopping; climbing like a spider's thread.
何処もかしこもクソだらけってオイ一番クソなのはオマエだ馬鹿
Everywhere is full of crap—hey, the biggest piece of crap is you, idiot!
良いとか悪いとか言うそれ以前に 俺には一切記憶がねえんだよ
Even before talking about good or bad, I have absolutely no memory left!
嫌になるぜもう限界 飲んでもいないのに難なく生きてる
I'm sick of it, I've reached my limit. Living so effortlessly without even drinking—
アンタの方こそ飲まれてるんだよ 嫌になるぜもう一杯
you're the one who's being consumed by it! It makes me sick, give me another drink.
愛だの恋だのやんややと騒ぐが
Making a fuss about love and romance,
酔ったら結局誰でもいいんだよ 荒ぶれて暴言タイム
once drunk, anyone is fine in the end—it's wild profanity time.
その「誰でも」すら俺は選ばれず 泣くのもダメさ酒を浴びたよ
Even for that "anyone," I'm not chosen. Can't even cry, so I drenched myself in alcohol.
嫌になるぜもう一杯 can't stop 意味もなくもう一杯
It makes me sick, another cup! Can't stop, another cup for no reason!
won't stop 死ぬ前にもう一杯
Won't stop, one more cup before I die!
ロボ子先輩 お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Roboco-senpai, happy birthday!
わあ ありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much!
いやぁまさか ついに一緒に歌って踊ってしまったんですね
I mean, I never thought we'd finally sing and dance together!
やっと 一緒に歌えてしまったよ
We finally got to sing together!
ねえ なんかさ 何人かでやることはあっても二人でやるっていうのは初めてですもんね
Hey, you know, even if we've done things in groups, it's our first time doing it just the two of us!
ねえ。でも、何にしようかなってすごい選曲迷って、めちゃめちゃ変えちゃったんだよね。
Hey. But I was really torn on what song to choose, and I ended up changing it a lot.
え？変えたの？
Eh? You changed it?
めちゃめちゃ黒髪に、え、これどうかな？これやりたい！やっぱこれでもいいって
Like, with super black hair... like, 'How about this? I wanna do this!' or 'Is this one okay too?'
ああ、それか、それか、そういうことかびっくりした。
Ah, I see. That's what you meant! You surprised me.
そうそうそう、めちゃめちゃ変えた。
Yeah, exactly, I changed it completely.
はいはいはいはい。
Right, right, right.
そう、で、こう、こういうやつで立っちゃった。
Yeah, and so, I ended up standing like this.
めちゃめちゃ合っていませんでした、我々。
We totally didn't match at all.
え、合ってた、合ってた。ちょっと酒飲みのあのポーズこれ、これめっちゃ好きなんだよね。
Eh, we matched! I really love that drinking pose.
ねえ、ここパッて外すの。
Hey, taking this part off with a snap—
そう。
Yeah.
いや似合うだ、めちゃめちゃ似合ってた、でも僕たち弱いんだよね。
It suits you, it suited you so well, but we're weak, aren't we?
うん、稽古です。
Yeah, that's rehearsal.
これ見せかけです、これ。
This is just for show, this is.
ねえ、しかも衣装もかわいいですよね、やっぱね。
And besides, the outfits are so cute too.
いや、似合ってるよ。これも結構シナジーあるよね。
Yeah, they suit us. This has pretty good synergy too.
ありますよね。え、これでもだんだん戻るんですか？
It really does. Eh, does it slowly go back to normal even after this?
と思うじゃ？
What do you think?
え？
Eh?
はい。
Yep.
もしもしかして、いやなんかちょっと、え、ど、どうなんだろうね？
Could it be...? No, wait, how, how is it going to be?
おーれ！おーれ！おーれ！おーれ！
Ole! Ole! Ole! Ole!
気になる！
I'm curious!
おーれ！おーれ！おーれ！おーれ！
Ole! Ole! Ole! Ole!
じゃあちょっとこの後も皆さん見守ってください。
Well, everyone, please keep watching us after this too.
お願いします！
Please do!
先輩がどうなるのか。
To see what happens to Senpai.
はい！
Yes!
ではでは、また遊びましょうね！
Well then, let's play again!
遊ぼうね！またね！ありがとう！バイバイ！
Let's hang out! See you! Thanks! Bye-bye!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
私が私のことを愛して何が悪いのか？
What's wrong with me loving myself?
嫉妬でしょうか？痛いとか変わってるとか
Is it jealousy? Calling me pathetic or eccentric—
届きませんね。そのリプライ
I can't hear those replies!
大好きなお洋服 大好きなお化粧で
In my favorite clothes and favorite makeup,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
With my iconic half-twintails curled,
お出かけしよう 日傘持って
Let's go out with my parasol!
ぼっちだって 幸せだもん！
I'm alone, but I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry that I was born
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatedly cute
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't take your eyes off me, right? Sorry
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working hard on myself
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being such a girly girl
ムカついてしまうよね？ざまぁw
It pisses you off, doesn't it? Too bad!
貴女は貴女のことだけどうぞ
You just worry about yourself
私に干渉しないでください
Please don't interfere with me
類は友を呼ぶと言うけれど…
They say birds of a feather flock together...
届きませんね。その陰口
But I can't hear those rumors behind my back
重い厚底ブーツ お気に入りのリュックで
Heavy platform boots, with my favorite backpack,
崩さない前髪 くしでといで
Fixing my bangs with a comb,
お出かけしよう 軽い女？ふざけんな
Let's go out! An easy woman? Are you kidding me?
重すぎるっつーの！
That's way too heavy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
この時代生きててごめん
Sorry for living in this era
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out
意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
You notice me, don't you? Sorry
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
自分磨きしててごめん
Sorry for polishing myself
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for acting cutesy
沼にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you in my trap
ムカついてしまうでしょ？ざまぁw
Does it piss you off? Too bad!
趣味の違い 変わり者と
Mocked as eccentric for having different hobbies
曲げたくない 怖くもない
I don't want to bend, I'm not scared either
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want my greatest ally to be myself
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to treasure myself the most
理不尽な我儘はさせたくない
I won't let unreasonable selfishness be forced on me
“それが私”
"That's me"
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry that I was born
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatedly cute
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying life
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working hard on myself
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being a girly girl
ムカついてしまうよね？ざまぁw
It pisses you off, doesn't it? Too bad!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry that I was born
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being calculatedly cute
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't take your eyes off me, right? Sorry
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working hard on myself
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being precious
女子力高くてごめん...
Sorry for being a girly girl...
思い出すのは君の歌
What I remember is your song,
会話よりも鮮明だ
more vividly than conversation.
どこに行ってしまったね
Where did you go off to?
いつも探すんだよ
I'm always searching for it.
思い出すのは君の歌
What I remember is your song,
歌い笑う顔が鮮明だ
your face singing and laughing is so clear.
君に似合うんだよ
It really suits you.
ずっと見ていたいよ
I want to keep looking at it forever.
でも最後に観たいのはきっともう君の夢の中
But what I want to see at the end is in your dream,
もう一度また聞かせてくれよ
let me hear it once more.
聞きたいんだ
I want to hear it.
もっと騒げ怪獣の歌
Roar more, monster's song,
まだ消えない夢の歌歌って
sing the dream's song that still won't fade away!
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
The monster's song you always sang, I still catch myself humming it.
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sang,
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I still catch myself humming it.
君がいた ギター持ってる
You were there, holding a guitar,
君がいた 忘れられないんだよ
you were there, I can never forget it.
だから僕が歌うよ
That's why I will sing!
でも最後に観たいのはきっともう君の夢の中
But what I want to see at the end is in your dream,
もう一度また聞かせてくれよ
let me hear it once more.
聞きたいんだ
I want to hear it.
もっと騒げ怪獣の歌
Roar more, monster's song,
まだ消えない夢の歌歌って
sing the dream's song that still won't fade away!
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
The monster's song you always sang, I still catch myself humming it.
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sang,
まだ消えない夢の歌
the song of an undying dream,
と鳴いて君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
echoing... the monster's song you always sang,
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I still catch myself humming it.
落ちてく過去は鮮明で
The falling past is so clear,
見せたい未来は繊細で
the future I want to show is delicate,
過ぎてく日々に苛むんだ君へ
tormenting the passing days, towards you.
もっと騒げ怪獣の歌
Roar more, monster's song,
まだ消えない夢の歌歌って
sing the dream's song that still won't fade away!
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
The monster's song you always sang, I still catch myself humming it.
君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
The monster's song you always sang,
まだ消えない夢の歌
the song of an undying dream,
と鳴いて君がいつも歌う怪獣の歌
echoing... the monster's song you always sang,
まだ消えない口ずさんでしまうよ
I still catch myself humming it.
ねぇ僕ら
Hey, us,
眠れない夜に手を伸ばして
reaching out our hands into sleepless nights,
眠れない夜をまた伸ばして
reaching out once more into sleepless nights,
眠くないまだね
still not sleepy yet,
そんな日々でいたいのにさ
even though I wanted to stay in days like that,
懲りずに
without learning our lesson.
ねぇ僕ら
Hey, us,
眠れない夜に手を伸ばして
reaching out our hands into sleepless nights,
眠れない夜をまた伸ばして
reaching out once more into sleepless nights,
眠くないまだね
still not sleepy yet,
そんな夜に歌う
singing in such a night,
怪獣の歌
the monster's song.
眠れない夜に手を伸ばして
Reaching out into sleepless nights,
眠れない夜をまた伸ばして
reaching out once more into sleepless nights,
眠くないまだね
still not sleepy yet,
そんな夜に歌う怪獣の歌
singing the monster's song in such a night.
袋に詰められたナッツのような世間では
In a world like nuts packed in a bag,
誰もがそれぞれで出会った誰かと寄り添い合っている
everyone is snuggling up to someone they met.
そこに紛れ込んだ僕らはピーナッツみたいに
We, mixed in there, like peanuts,
木の実のフリをしながら微笑み浮かべる
keep smiling while pretending to be tree nuts.
噛み砕いても無くならない本音が歯に挟まったままで
Even when chewed up, real feelings stay stuck in my teeth,
不安だらけ成り行き任せの life and I know
full of anxiety, leaving things to fate, and I know.
袋に詰められたナッツのような世界では
In a world like nuts packed in a bag,
誰もがそれぞれ出会った誰かと寄り添い合っている
Everyone snuggles up with someone they met.
そこに紛れ込んだ僕らは
We, mixed in there,
ピーナッツみたいに 木の実のフリしながら微笑み浮かべる
Look like peanuts, smiling as if we're nuts.
幸せのテンプレートの上
On the template of happiness,
文字通り絵に描いたような裏表
Behind the picturesque surface,
テーブルを囲み手を合わせるその時さえ
Gathering around the table to join hands,
ありのままでは居られないまま
We cannot even be ourselves.
隠し事ばかり 継ぎ接ぎだらけのhome you know
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
噛み砕いても無くならない 本音が歯に挟まったまま
Even if I chew it up, it still gets stuck in my teeth.
不安ばかり 成り行き任せのlife and I know
An insecure, go-with-the-flow life, and I know.
仮初めまみれの日常だけど
Every day is just a cliché, but...
ここに僕が居て あなたが居る
I am here, and you are here.
この事実だけでもう胃もたれていく
Just knowing this truth, my stomach already aches.
化けの皮が剥がれた一粒のピーナッツみたいに
Like a single peanut peeled of its disguise,
世間から一瞬で弾かされてしまう
Instantly rejected from society.
そんな時こそ 曲がりなりで良かったらそばに居させて
When that happens, I want to be by your side.
共に煎られ 揺られ 踏まれても
Roasted, shaken, and stepped on together,
割れない殻みたいになるから
We'll become unbreakable nutshells.
生まれた場所が木の上か 地面の中か
Whether born on a tree or in the ground,
それだけの違い 許されないほどに
That's the only difference.
ドライなこの世界を 等しく雨が湿らせますように
May the rain equally moisten this dry world,
時に冷たくて 騒がしい窓の向こうyou know
Sometimes cold and noisy outside the window, you know?
星のいくつかも見つからない
It's okay if we can't see the stars,
雷に満ちた日があっても良い
Or if there are days filled with thunder.
ミスばかり アドリブ任せのshow but I know
A show full of mistakes and improvisation, but I know.
所詮ひとけの日常だから
After all, it's just daily life,
腹の中ででも 流して寝よう
So let's digest it in our guts and sleep.
隠し事ばかり 継ぎ接ぎだらけのhome you know
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
とっておきも 出会い頭も 残さずに全部食らいながら
Let's eat up everything, leaving nothing behind.
普通なんてない 正解なんてないlife and I know
There is no normal, no right answer in life, and I know.
仮初めまみれの日常だけど
Every day is just a cliché, but...
ここに僕が居て あなたが居る
I am here, and you are here.
この事実だけでもう胃もたれていく
Just knowing this truth, my stomach already aches.
雷に免れても 神隠しで謎解きがあってもいい
Even if lightning flashes and I'm caught,
水浸しだけ あたりぶっかまかせのショーばたのう
With water everywhere and an improvised show,
囁きとかけらの日常だから
Whispers and fragmented daily life,
腹の中だけでも 流して寝よう
Even deep inside the belly, let's just let it flow and sleep.
隠し事ばかり 継ぎ接ぎだらけのhome you know
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
とっておきも出来合いも
Let's fight it out head-on,
残さず全部食らうから 普通なんてない 正解なんてないのよ
Without holding back, swallowing it all down.
隠し事ばかり 継ぎ接ぎだらけのhome you know
A home full of secrets and patches, you know?
噛み砕いても無くならない 本音が歯に挟まったまま
Even if I chew it up, it still gets stuck in my teeth.
ここに僕が居て あなたが居る
I am here, and you are here.
この事実だけでもう胃もたれていく
Just knowing this truth, my stomach aches.
この一つ一つの奇跡を噛み締めていく
And I'll cherish this miracle, piece by piece.
ロボ子お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday to Roboco!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日はね ミックスナッツをお届けしたくて
Today, we wanted to sing "Mixed Nuts."
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
ずっと前から私の父と母のルリとトワに来てもらいました！
And we had both of our moms come join us today!
来てくれましたね ここで
They really came, lol!
私も勝手に母にされちゃいました 高根ルイでーす
I also casually made my mom Takane Lui.
いつもお世話になってます
Always here to help!
じゃあ我々結婚していたということでよろしくお願いします
So we were married, huh? Nice to meet you.
めっちゃ悲しいんだけどなんでそんなこと言うの
I'm actually quite sad, why are you saying that?
くそー！
You're so mean!
あれ？なんか 衣装が？そういえばこれ、確かにマシよね？
Wait, our outfits... come to think of it,
そうなんです、こちら新しいショートとなっておりまーす
That's right, this is our new short outfit!
かーい！
So cute!
ちょっとスポーティーな感じで
It's a bit sporty.
普段はいつもなんだこうクールビューティーって感じじゃね
Usually it's cool, but this is cute and beautiful.
そうなの、露出してるのもなんかポカーンって
That's right, exposing our midriff like this, pow!
ちょっとセクシーでいいよね 見せられません
It's a bit sexy, right? Can't help looking.
おい見せろよ 映せよ
Hey, show us! Put it on display!
そうなんです、こちらの僕かわいいでしょう？
Right, so this belly of mine is cute, isn't it?
かわいい。ちらっちらっ
Cute! Let's peek a little.
そうなん、で、でも
So, actually...
これ...パーカー脱けちゃうんだよね
This outfit... the parka actually comes off!
え？パーカー？実話...脱けちゃうの？
Eh? The parka? It comes off?
え、ちょっとYouTubeくん大丈夫かな？
Is YouTube-kun okay with that?
イェーイ！明日リコンします！
Yay! Let's get it in tomorrow!
のぶぶ分が出てるんだけど、うん。
My usual vibe is showing, yeah,
今回は一味違うんですよ！
this time it's a little different!
いーじゃん！なんか背中も可愛くない？
That's great! Doesn't your back look cute too?
え、どうどうどう？
Eh, how is it, how is it?
え、いーじゃん！
Eh, looks great!
どうですー？
How is it?
ふりふりふりふりー！
Furi furi furi furi!
ねぇ、ちょっと待って！
Hey, wait a minute!
それもうなんて呼んでるか分からないからやめてよ
Stop, I don't even know what you're calling that!
ボクでも可愛いんだから！
Even I am cute, you know!
どうすんの、ボクが爆発しちゃったら君たちも！
What'll happen if I explode? You guys too—!
でもボタン押しやすそうだね
Though that button looks easy to press.
え、確かに。ちょっと押しやすいんだよね
True. It's a bit easy to press, huh.
ちょっと衝動があるんだけど我慢してもろっていいですか
I have a bit of an urge, but can you bear with it?
じゃあ、なんかお知らせがあるということなんで、そのボタンを押しましょうかね。ポチッ！
Well, let's press that button. Pochit!
だめー！
No!
まあなんですけど、何もないですけど！
Well, though there's nothing!
はい！はい！お知らせは本当にあります！こちらー！
Yes! There really is an announcement! Here!
はい、というわけでロボコのグッズが出ます！誕生日記念2023！まず1つ目は、こちらです！
Yes, so Roboco's merch is coming out! Birthday 2023! First is this!
どどん！アクリルスタンドー！かわいいー！
Dodonn! An acrylic stand! So cute!
今回のこの髪型で衣装で、え、VERI先生にスイッチと一緒に描いていただきましたー！
VERI-sensei drew this with Switch for my new look!
めっちゃ可愛くない？かわいい！可愛いよね！
Isn't it super cute? So cute!
食べちゃいたいね。食べちゃいたいよね！そうだよね！
I wanna eat you up. I really do! Right!
意味深なこと言うな！
Don't say such suggestive things!
まだね、まだ分かんないからみんなには。
It's still a secret to everyone yet.
じゃあ次のやつを見てみましょう。次こちら！
Let's check out the next one. Next is this!
ランダム缶バッジ！こちらまちこまき先生に描いていただきました！
Random can badge! Drawn by Machikomaki-sensei!
いろんな衣装と髪型のロボコだ。新しいやつのこれも可愛いですね、いろんな種類があって
Various outfits and hairstyles. This new one is cute too!
全部集めたい。どれにしようっかな。ランダムだから選べません！
I want them all. Which one should I pick? Random, so I can't choose!
全部ゲットしてみてくださーい！
Please try to get them all!
はい、そして次は、こちら！スマホリングー！おしゃれー！
Yes, and next is this! Smartphone ring! Stylish!
そう、今回ステージにも歯車のやつをモチーフいっぱい付けさせていただいたんですけど
We had gear motifs all over the stage this time too,
スマホリングも今回ロゴ入りで歯車のやつにさせていただきました！
and the ring also features the logo and gear design!
チャームもね、取ったり外したりもできるの、取ったり外したり。付け替えができるのでぜひぜひ
The charm can be attached and detached, so please check it out!
そして次は、こちら！ロボ子さんとおそろいボディバッグー！じゃじゃーん！なんとこれじゃん！
And next is this! Matching body bag! Ta-da! What, this?!
ボクと同じバッグがゲットできます！いいなこれ！
You can get the same bag as me!
結構ね、ポリキャンパス系なのでしっかりした素材で作られてるので、普段使いめちゃしやすいと思います
It's sturdy poly-canvas, great for daily use.
運動しながらこれけっつけるっていうのね
Putting this on while exercising, huh.
是非是非どうですか？欲しい欲しい！一緒にこれつけようね！
How is it? I want it! Let's wear this together!
欲しい、父と母にはくれますか？あげます！やったー！見つけてくださーい！
Will you give one to dad and mom? I'll give it! Yay!
やばい父と母ばれしちゃうのこれ、ていうか
Oh no, this reveals my dad and mom.
家族とロボコの家族とおそろいボディバッグだね
A matching body bag with your family.
これがなかったら父と母になってくれなかったってこと？ちょっと待って
If not for this, they wouldn't have been my parents?
明日にはりこんだんだけどねえ
I put so much effort into tomorrow.
そんな残虐なこと押し付けちゃだめだね、ごめんごめんごめん
You shouldn't force such cruel things. Sorry!
はい、最後は、こちら！記念ボイス、シチュエーションボイス「ボクと過ごす甘いひと時」ボイス販売もあります！
And finally, the voice pack "Sweet moments with me"!
あら、甘いひと時ね。ボクちょっと大人になっちゃった。
Oh, a sweet time. I've become an adult.
あーなるほどね、じゃあもう1人立ちできるということで
Ah I see, so you can live independently—
違う違う違う違う違う違う！なんかまずい方向になってるから早く早く！
No no no! It's going somewhere bad, hurry!
はいというわけでこちらですね、フルセット購入にはもちろん数量限定で、ボクの直筆サインと複製メッセージ入りのポストカードがついてきます！
Full set comes with a signed and message postcard!
もちろん通常版にもサインとメッセージ入りのポストカードがありますので、ぜひフルセットで購入してみてください！
Regular version has it too, so buy the full set!
数量限定だから急ぎを！
It's limited quantity, so hurry!
はいというわけで、ということで大人になったねロボコ。
So, Roboco became an adult.
旅立ちの日。そうかね、もうママとパパはいらないね。
The day of departure. We don't need mom and dad.
いる！いるけど、いるけど！
We do! But we do!
じゃあこの辺で
Well, around here—
寝なかった。待って！
Didn't sleep. Wait!
ギブ父と母、やばいケツが、ケツが
Give dad and mom... oh, my butt is—
え、待って、ボクこれさ
Wait, me and this...
父と母はケツがあります！
Dad and mom have butts!
レンタルパパ、レンタルママ！
Rental papa, rental mama!
今日もレンタル疲れちゃったな
I got tired of renting today too.
待って、ボクってこれレンタル父と母だったってこと？心が虚しいんだけど。
Were they rental parents? My heart feels empty.
でもありがとう、またねー！
But thanks, see you again!
ねぇねぇ 言いたいことが
Hey, hey, there are so many things I want to say,
たくさんあるけど オーバーヒート
but I'm overheating.
ぐるぐる回る 頭の中
Spinning round and round in my head,
転んでも笑って側にいてね
even if I fall, smile and stay by my side.
転んでも笑ってそばにいてね
Even if I stumble, stay by my side, okay?
全然足りないスペック
My specs are totally lacking,
でも気合万全
but my spirit's 100% ready,
やる気も満タン
and my motivation's full!
伝わるといいな君に for you
Hope it reaches you, for you—
ポンでもきらきら輝きたい glory days
Even if I'm clumsy, I want to shine bright in these glory days!
なんだかんだまずいちゃうの
Somehow things always go a bit wrong,
パーフェクトにクールにしたいのに
Even though I want to be perfect and cool,
こんがらがると配線もつれる手足
My tangled wiring and tangled limbs—
始終こんなんじゃ
Always ending up like this,
満身創痍
battered and bruised.
たまには高性能って言われたい
Sometimes I want to be called high-spec!
意地悪だってしちゃいたいねいいでしょ
I want to tease you a bit too, is that okay?
モロバレのブラフでも分からないふりをして
Even with a totally obvious bluff, act like you don't know
ボクに騙されてよ
and let yourself be fooled by me!
ねぇねぇ言いたいことが
Hey, hey, there are so many things
たくさんあるけどオーバーヒート
I want to say, but I'm overheating!
ぐるぐる回る頭の中
Inside my spinning, dizzy head,
転んでも笑ってそばにいてね
Even if I stumble, stay by my side, okay?
全然足りないスペック
My specs are totally lacking,
でも気合万全
but my spirit's 100% ready,
やる気も満タン
and my motivation's full!
伝わるといいな君に for you
Hope it reaches you, for you—
ポンでもきらきら輝きたい glory days
Even if I'm clumsy, I want to shine bright in these glory days!
現実もゲームのようにバチッと決めれたらいいのにな
I wish real life could snap into place like a video game,
焦燥感積み木メンタル
With my impatience stacking up like Jenga blocks of mental health.
今朝胡椒を嗅いだらむせちゃったおあち
This morning when I smelled pepper, I choked up, oh dear!
ジーニアス手元にペンデュラム
Genius pendulums in hand,
指し示せ行くべき道を
Point the way I should go!
難しすぎてわからないままでまたポンしちゃうよ
It's too hard to understand, and I end up messing up again!
ねぇねぇ言いたいことが
Hey, hey, there are so many things
たくさんあるけどオーバーヒート
I want to say, but I'm overheating!
ぐるぐる回る頭の中
Inside my spinning, dizzy head,
転んでも笑ってそばにいてね
Even if I stumble, stay by my side, okay?
全然足りないスペック
My specs are totally lacking,
でも気合万全
but my spirit's 100% ready,
やる気も満タン
and my motivation's full!
伝わるといいな君に for you
Hope it reaches you, for you—
ポンでもきらきら輝きたい glory days
Even if I'm clumsy, I want to shine bright in these glory days!
ねぇねぇ言いたいことが
Hey, hey, there are so many things
たくさんあるけどオーバーヒート
I want to say, but I'm overheating!
ぐるぐる回る頭の中
Inside my spinning, dizzy head,
転んでも笑ってそばにいてね
Even if I stumble, stay by my side, okay?
全然足りないスペック
My specs are totally lacking,
でも気合万全
but my spirit's 100% ready,
やる気も満タン
and my motivation's full!
伝わるといいな君に for you
Hope it reaches you, for you—
ポンでもきらきら輝きたい glory days
Even if I'm clumsy, I want to shine bright in these glory days!
ろぼさへ いつもそばで見守ってくれてありがとう
To Robosa—thank you for always watching over me by my side.
今日で7歳になったんだけど多分今日の配信のどこかでちょっとポンしたところがあったんだけど気づけちゃった人いるかなぁ
Today I turned 7, but I probably made a little silly mistake somewhere in today's stream... I wonder if anyone noticed?
まあそれは後日談でどっかで話したいなって思うんだけど今日みたいに多分まだまだポンなこともしちゃうと思うけど
Well, I'd love to talk about that somewhere later on, and like today, I'll probably still do clumsy things...
でも高性能なんだよねもっと高性能なところもいっぱい見せていきたいなって思います
But I am high-spec, right? I hope to show you even more of my high-spec side!
でもポンコツな僕をいつも愛してくれてありがとうこれからも温かい目で見守ってください
But thank you for always loving clumsy ol' me. Please continue to watch over me with warm eyes.
たくさんたくさん新しい思い出つくろうね大好き
Let's make lots and lots of new memories together. Love you!
またね たくさん♡大好き♡
See you again! Lots of love ♡